olando **Garcia**

23 Glebe Rd. West, Apt. 23, Toronto, ON M5P 0A1, Canada

□ (+1) 416-414-3370 | **☑** rolygarcor@gmail.com | **□** rolando-garcia-423759141

Professional Summary

Assistant broker with over 3 years of professional experience providing insurance expertise to clients, spanning over various lines of commercial business. Providing high proficiency in insurance laws within Ontario adhering to RIBO regulations along with prominent communication skills and a constructive attitude.

Experience

HUB International Toronto, ON

COMMERCIAL LINES ACCOUNT ASSISTANT, REAL ESTATE

Nov. 2019 - Present

- Team player, providing assistance with a variety of accounts where required.
- Assist clients by answering questions, and issuing Certificates and Liability Slips as required.
- Acquiring Loss Runs, Perform analysis to determine Risks and Loss Ratios.
- · Handle Renewals all the way from creating submissions for Marketing Accounts to creating Proposals for clients.
- Analyze Policies and Binders to determine client requirements.
- · Assisting with the execution of Insurance Certificates, Liability Slips, Binders, Proposal, Statements of Value, and Endorse-
- Handle Billing and Invoicing in a timely manner and follow up with clients for payment.
- · Provide timely updates to account managers.
- · Spearhead of the ETIP program.

Aon Reed Stenhouse Inc. Toronto, ON

ANALYST, STRATEGIC RISK ADVISORY GROUP

May. 2018 - Nov. 2019

- · Manage a diverse portfolio of over 23 client relationships which include major companies in the commercial real estate, retail, mining and investment industries such as TD Canada Trust and UBER.
- Execute policy renewals in coordination with the internal and external stakeholders.
- · Analyze and interpret upwards of 30 legal contracts and Certificate requests daily to process insurance policies for clients' books of business, ensuring continuous risk coverage that accommodates their requirements.
- Review, edit and maintain Xpress Certificate history to manage and control quality.
- · Aid account assistants and account managers as required and assist the department with testing and implementation of new
- · Identify and target policy issues on daily requests, as well as reinforce customer service priorities through periodic follow ups to develop exceptional relationships.

Aboriginal Insurance Services Inc.

Toronto, ON

ASSISTANT

May. 2014 - Aug. 2014

- · Use company proprietary systems to analyze exposures and loss history to determine adequate pricing procedures and cov-
- Assist underwriters in the preparation of quotes and binders, as well as endorsements to existing policies.
- · Clerical tasks and data entry in the underwriting department, relating to commercial insurance.

Skills

Broker Tools Xpress, Applied Epic.

Microsoft Office Excel, Word, Outlook, Powerpoint, Skype, Teams, Access.

Soft Skills Adaptable, Dependable, Strong work ethic, Friendly attitude, Clear & concise communication, Motivated.

Languages English, Spanish.

Education

Carleton University Ottawa, Canada

BACHELOR OF ECONOMICS Sept. 2013 - April. 2017

Taught by seasoned experienced economists who have a keen understanding of the discipline and are recognized for their excellence in teaching and research.

Certifications & Licenses

2019 Registered Insurance Brokers of Ontario, RIBO Toronto, ON

JANUARY 24, 2021 ROLANDO GARCIA · RÉSUMÉ